{
    "id": "03f2cc42c21a4a10b3898f11a4ce65f2",
    "title": "Conditional Clauses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "........................... someone gives me a lift, I won't be able to reach office on time.",
            "description": "Unless means if not.",
            "answers": [
                "Unless",
                "If",
                "Whether"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I will come with you if you ...................................... for my drink.",
            "description": "In first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "pay",
                "paid",
                "have paid"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": ".......................... you don't wear a coat, you may catch a cold.",
            "description": "We use if to express a condition.",
            "answers": [
                "If",
                "Whether",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I ........................... a cake if it is your birthday.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if clause and will + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will bake",
                "would bake",
                "would have baked"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If she ............................. in Bangkok, she may visit her cousins.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I could buy a laptop, if I ................................. more money.",
            "description": "In type 2 conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and could / would + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "have",
                "had",
                "had had"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ............................... the jackpot, what would you do?",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "win",
                "won",
                "had won"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You ................................. fewer health problems if you stop eating junk food.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will have",
                "would have",
                "would have had",
                ""
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If I hadn't broken my leg, I .................................... hiking with my cousins.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will go",
                "would go",
                "would have gone"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If I had his number, I ................................ him.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will call",
                "would call",
                "would have called"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If you arrived early, you ................................. the show.",
            "description": "In type 2 conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "don't miss",
                "won't miss",
                "wouldn't miss"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If she had called, I ...................................",
            "description": "In type 3 conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will go",
                "would go",
                "would have gone"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}